嘿，你们好，我是TheCherno，欢迎来到我的游戏引擎系列
hey, what's up guys, my name is TheCherno, and welcome to my game engine series
那样说的感觉真好，这个系列已经制作了两年，我们终于可以开始了
feels so good to say that this series has been in the making for like two years, and we're finally beginning
并且今天我们要讨论的是，什么是游戏引擎
and today suitably I think we're gonna be talking about, what a game engine actually is
因为在我们开始做之前，最好先定义一下我们要做什么
because before we start making one, it's probably a good idea to actually define what we're going to be making
并且在接下来的几期视频中，我们将开始专门设计这个游戏引擎
and over the next kind of few videos, we are going to start planning this game engine specifically
所以一定要看看后面几期视频，它们很快就发出来
so definitely check out those later videos, they will come out very very soon
但首先，在我开始之前，我想对所有的赞助人说声非常感谢，是他们促成了这个系列
but first of all before I begin, I just want to say a huge thank you to all of the patreons who made this series happen
patreon.com/TheCherno是我的patreon，如果你们想支持我的话，可以去看看
patreon.com/TheCherno is my patreon, if you guys want to support me
那就太棒了，因为正是那样才有了这一切，你们的持续支持对我来说非常非常重要
then that would be absolutely amazing, because that is what makes this possible, and your continued support is very very important to me
所以非常感谢你们每一个人，因为没有你们，我就不会坐在这儿
so huge thank you to everyone, because I wouldn't be here without you
所以我能做到这一切真是太棒了
so it's just so amazing that I can do this
因为我想做这件事很久了，是你们给了我机会和时间来做这件事
because I've wanted to do this for so long, and you've given me the opportunity and the time to actually do this
好了，无论如何，在第一期计划视频中，正如我想说的，我们基本上只是讨论
okay, so anyway, in this first kind of set of planning videos, as I want to say, we're going to be basically just talking about
游戏引擎到底是什么，就是游戏引擎，对吧，游戏引擎已经存在一段时间了
what a game engine actually is, so game engines, right, they've been around for a while
它们是什么，我们为什么需要它们，我们真的需要它们吗
what are they, why do we need them, do we even need them
以及在这个系列中我们实际上要做些什么
and what is it that we're actually going to be making in this series
所以人们对游戏引擎的定义非常宽泛，比如
so people have very very broad definitions of game engines ranging from everything from like
那只是帮助你们快速创造游戏的工具
oh, it's just something that helps you kind of build games quickly
内容创建者可以使用全套工具来制作模型等等
to like full kind of suite of like tools the content creators can use to make models and everything like that
我的意思是，如果你们上网搜一下游戏引擎到底是什么
and I mean, if you kind of just go on the internet, and search for a minute like what a game engine actually is
以及关于游戏引擎的例子，你们可能会搜到Unity或Unreal等引擎，对吧
and what examples of game engines are, you'll probably stumble up on engine such as Unity or Unreal, right
并且那些引擎都是游戏引擎的例子，它们已经商业化了，我想已经向公众开放了
and those engines are examples of game engines, that have been kind of commercialized, and kind of I guess released out into the public
要么是免费的，要么是订阅计划，或者是某种版税协议，对吧
either for free or kind of on subscription plans, or on some kind of royalty agreement, right
并且它们本质上表现为一组工具
and they kind of present themselves essentially as a set of tools
就像关卡编辑器这样的大型工具，你们可以在其中创造游戏
like a one big tool usually like a level editor, pretty much in which you can actually build your game
它就更像是一种平台，用来构建交互式应用程序
it's like a kind of platform pretty much, for building an interactive kind of application
不一定非得是游戏，它的核心就是交互应用
doesn't even have to necessarily be a game, it's just really at its core an interactive application
现在，那些就是你们看到的，暴露在外面的，对吧
now, those are the ones that you kind of see, that are out in the wild, right
因为它们已经在宣传中商业化了，我想就像游戏引擎一样，那就是产品
because they've been kind of commercialized in publicize, I guess as specifically as game engines, that is the product
产品就是游戏引擎，但对很多公司来说，这甚至不是，比如你们知道的
the product is the game engine, but for a lot of companies, it's not even about, you know
制作游戏引擎，那并不是他们的产品
making a game engine, that's not their product
他们的产品只是一款游戏，那么我们来看看所有这些电子游戏公司
their product is a game, and so we look at all of these video game companies
比如育碧，比如你们知道的，动视，暴雪和维尔福
like AAUbisoft, you know, whatever Activision, Blizzard, Valve
他们都拥有自己的内部引擎，但从未作为真正的游戏引擎面世
they have their own in house engines that they've built, that never see the light of day as an actual game engine
它们并没有作为游戏引擎对外发布，公司之外的人无权使用它们作为游戏引擎，
they're not released as a game engine, no one has access to them outside of the company as a game engine
它们都是内部的，对吧
they're all internal, right
但他们所提供的是一个平台，让游戏团队的工作人员能够真正构建游戏，真正构建游戏
but what they do provide is a platform for the staff working on those game teams to actually construct that game, to actually build that game
所以当我们提到一款游戏时，我真正想要强调的是，它只是一个平台
so when we think about a game mention, what I really want to kind of push forward is the idea of it's a platform
你们可以用它来制作电子游戏，并且游戏这个词也是我经常提到的
which you can use to build video games, and the term game again is something that I keep coming back to
因为假设，比如你们知道的，现实点说吧，那不一定是一个游戏
because hypothetic, you know, realistically speaking, it doesn't have to be a game
现在这些游戏工作室，他们的产品是游戏，所以他们就用这些引擎制作游戏
now these game studios, their products are games, so they do build games with these engines
但如果你们看看Unreal或Unity之类的引擎，它们可以用于更多领域，而不仅仅是游戏
but if you look at something like Unreal or Unity, they can be used for much more than just in games
它们可以用于构建VR应用，如建筑可视化，甚至在某些情况下也可以用来模拟
they can be used for building VR applications like architectural visualizations, even in some cases simulations
那显然需要很多额外的代码，但它们可以作为一种构建应用的方式
which again obviously would require a lot of additional code, but they could just be used as a way to kind of build an application
呈现生命周期类型的实时应用，对吧，本质上，我说的是
kind of rendering life cycle type real time application thing, right, essentially what I'm saying is
如果你们想要一个实时显示图形的应用
if you want an application that displays graphics in real time
那么你们就可以使用Unity或Unreal去可视化你们所拥有的任何数据，对吧
you could just use Unity or Unreal to visualize whatever data you have, right
最重要的是，它不仅仅是可视化，它还涉及到许多平台上的互动，甚至是VR，对吧
and on top of that, it's not just even about visualization, it's also about interaction on a number of platforms even VR, right
它是一个完整的平台，可以让你们把拥有的数据转换成一个更具交互性的
it's a whole kind of platform for you to actually kind of convert the data that you have into a more interactable kind of
或者它会得到交互式的视觉格式，并且那就是我对游戏引擎的定义
or it gets interactive visual format, and that's where my definition of game engines kind of comes in
并且我想让你们花一分钟时间思考一下，我们正在构建的是什么，游戏引擎到底是什么
and I want you to just think about for a minute, what it is we're building, and what a game engine actually is
那才是核心，对吧，让我们简化整个事情，把它降低一个档次，以及真正思考一下
that's core, right, let's simplify this whole thing, let's take it down a notch and actually think about
好，那行吧，它是一个制作游戏的平台，但它到底是什么
well okay good, it's a platform to build games, but what is it really
归结到这一点，并且在我继续之前，先喝杯咖啡
it comes down to this, and before I continue, coffee
感觉不能没有咖啡啊，不管如何，游戏引擎在哪里，是了，那么什么是游戏引擎呢
where would we be without coffee, anyway, where are the game engines, yes, so what is a game engine as call
它的基本功能是，或者至少它的目标是将数据从一种格式转换成另一种格式
well basically what it is is, a or at least its goal is to transform data from one format into another
那就是数据转换的全部内容，对吧，我们从桌面读取一组文件
that's what this is all about data transformation, right, we essentially read in a set of files from desk
we take the data from those files, and we transform it into something else, that shows up on our screens
我们从那些文件中提取数据，然后把它转换成的其他东西，显示在我们的屏幕上
好了，就是那样，而且我们几乎总是提供一种与数据交互的方式，但那就是游戏引擎
okay, that's it, and furthermore we almost always provide a way to interact with that data as well, but that's really all the game engine is
并且那就是我们要构建的东西，它能读取数据，并把它转换成我们在屏幕上看到的东西
and that's what we're going to be building something that reads data in, and transforms it into something that we see on our screens
现在，因此我想说的是，我们必须意识到，从本质上来说，那才是真正的游戏引擎
now, because of the way, I phrase that it's important to realize that, at its core, that's really what a game engine is
它不是硬编码的程序应用，来做一些特定的事情，对吧
it's not a hard coded kind of programmed application, that just does certain things, right
如果你们在构建那种的话，很可能只是在构建一个应用程序或一个框架
if you're building that, you're probably most likely actually just building an application or a framework for an application like that
我们要做的是读取文件，转换它们，并且然后把它们放到屏幕上
what we're building is something that reads files in transforms them and then puts them on the screen
并且也增加了交互能力，那才是我们要构建的，并且那真的很简单
and adds you know interactive capabilities to that as well, that's what we're building, and that's really as simple as it is
正因为如此，我们必须意识到游戏引擎是基于数据的
so because of that, it's important to realize the game engines that extremely data oriented
这意味着游戏引擎的目的不是凭空创造数据，对吧
meaning that the purpose of a game engine is not to kind of create data based on nothing, right
我们在任何时候都不会那样做，对吧，我们只是加载现有文件
we're not doing that at any point like ever, right, what we're doing is we're just loading existing files
现在让我们关注一下文件，这些文件来自哪里，它们是什么，我们如何制作它们
now let's focus on the files for a second, where are these files coming from, what are they, how do we make them
那也是游戏引擎的一部分，它是制作那些文件的平台
that is also part of what a game engine is, it's a platform to make those files
现在我们称这些文件为资产，资产是指游戏引擎将其作为输入的文件
now we call these files assets, an asset is just something a file that the game engine actually takes in as input
我说过文件，它不一定是物理文件，但本质上，它只是一堆数据
now I did say a file, it doesn't have to be a physical file, but essentially, it's just a bunch of data
它可能是一个虚拟文件，也可能是游戏引擎在运行时创建的东西，对吧
it could be a virtual file, or it could be something that the game engine creates while running, right
那是基于其他资产，比如资产可以告诉游戏引擎去创造另一个资产
that is based on some other asset, like an asset could tell the game engine to create another asset for example
在运行时，那也是一种资产，即使它是在一个物理文件中，但我想说的是
on the fly, that would also be an asset, even though it's on a physical file, but what I'm saying is
提到的游戏通常包含一个平台，一套能够创造这些资产的工具，对吧
a game mentioned typically includes a platform, a suite of tools that can create these assets, right
它为我们创造了一种创建资产的方式，现在我的意思是，想象某人为游戏创建一个关卡
it creates a way for us to actually author assets, now what I mean by that is, picture someone building a level for a game
或者构建一个3D模型或者一个纹理，或者类似的东西
or maybe building a 3D model or a texture or something like that
一个艺术家或内容创造者将进入游戏工作室的结构中
an artist or a content creator will actually go in in a game studio structure
内容创造者将使用游戏引擎工具，对吧，去创建那些资产
a content creator will use game engine tools, right, to actually author those assets
现在他们可能会在Photoshop中制作纹理，但他们可能会在3DMax或Maya中创建3D模型
now they might make a texture in a Photoshop , but they might make a 3D model in like 3D Studio Sax or Maya
或者类似的东西，对吧，或者Blender什么的，对吧，但归根结底的说
or something like that, right, or Blender whatever, right, but at the end of the day
他们仍然需要将这个3D模型转换成游戏引擎能够接受的格式
they still need to get that model that 3D model into a format that the game engine can actually receive
因为对于真正的大型游戏引擎来说
because for like kind of real serious kind of big game engines
他们从来不会只接收，比如你们知道的，jpeg或png图像
it's pretty much never happens that they just take in, like you know, jpeg or png images
或者就像对象模型或者类似的东西，那不会发生，对吧
or like just kind of obj models or something like that, that doesn't happen, right
通常情况下，它们被构建成一种自定义的格式，那只是一个游戏引擎
usually they get built into a format, that's custom designed for that's just a game engine
无论是材质，模型，关卡等等，所以通常来说，内容创建者也会负责
whether it be textures models levels whatever, so typically speaking, that content creator would also be responsible for kind of
比如你们知道的，把那种3D部分格式的模型变成游戏引擎格式
you know, turning that kind of model in that 3D part format into the game engine format
这样就定义了一切，需要存在的东西，让游戏引擎用那个模型做一些事情
and thus kind of defining everything, that needs to exist for that game engine to actually do something with that model, right
因为通常来说，游戏引擎可能不只是包含在模型中的数据
because typically speaking, game engines probably have more than just the data that is included in a model as exported from like minor
它们可能有额外的信息，例如在世界的什么地方放置它，它上面可能有什么类型的其他组件
they might have additional information, such as where to place it in the world, what kind of other components it might have on it
它可能有什么功能，对吧，所有这些东西，所以那些基本上是内容创建者做的事情
what functionality might have on it, right, all that kind of stuff, so that is essentially what a content creator does
为游戏引擎创造内容，换句话说，内容创造者负责为游戏引擎创建资产
creates content for the game engine, so in other words, content creators are responsible for authoring assets for the game engine
然后游戏引擎在运行时读取这些资源，并在屏幕上呈现一些内容
and then the game engine reads those assets at runtime, and essentially presents something on the screen
并为用户提供一种与之交互的方式，并且那就是游戏，好了
and presents a way for the user to interact with that, and that is what a game is, okay
所以我们可以分解一个游戏引擎的所有系统
so we can break down all the systems of a game engine
一个游戏引擎有非常非常多的系统，显然取决于引擎
there are very very very many systems of a game engine, depends on the engine obviously
但我甚至，我在想也许可能不会，为什么现在要讲它
but I'm not even, I'm thinking that maybe probably wouldn't even be, why so kind of cover that now
我们可能会在下一期讲到这个，因为在下一期，我们会讲到游戏引擎的所有不同系统
we might just do that in the next episode, because in the next episode, we're going to kind of go through all the different systems of a game engine
并讨论我们将如何设计和实际实现它们
and talk about how we're going to design and actually implement them
但本质上是为了促进，我们所拥有的这种数据转换
but essentially in order to facilitate, this kind of data transformation that we have
我们需要很多不同的系统，包括我们想要的平台抽象层
we need a number of various systems, right, including like platform abstraction layers if we want
我们的引擎或数据转换将发生在各种平台上，不管是不是你们知道的
our engine or this data transformation to happen on a variety of platforms, whether that be you know
桌面平台，比如Windows MAC Linux
desktop based platforms like windows mac linux
或移动平台，比如Android IOS，或控制台平台，比如XBox PlayStation
or like mobile platforms like android ios, or console platforms like xbox playstation
比如你们知道的，任天堂之类的，我们需要平台抽象层，这样代码就可以在不同平台上运行
you know, Nintendo whatever, right, we need platform abstraction layers, so that our code can kind of run on different platforms
并且平台抽象层的重点当然是抽象那些平台，让我们平时不再关注那些平台的具体细节
and the point of a platform abstraction layer of course is to abstract those platforms, specific the platform details away from us
这样我们就可以编写适用于所有平台的通用代码
so that we can just write code that is generalized for all platforms
并且还有很多其他的，这里我就不一一讲了
and then there's many other I'm not even going to get into everything that game engines have
比如你们知道的，我们有渲染，音频，文件输入输出，序列化，有很多不同的东西，对吧
you know, we have rendering, we have kind of audio, we have like file input out, we have serialization, we have just so many different things, right
那些有助于这种数据转换，并且再次编写它们将是一次相当大的冒险
that facilitate this kind of data transformation, and again writing them is gonna be quite an adventure
所以我对整个系列都很兴奋，但除了这种运行时
so I'm really excited for this entire series, but apart from that kind of runtime
它将数据转换并将其放在那个集合的屏幕上并添加交互除此之外，比如你们知道的
which takes that data transforms it and puts it on the screen of that set and adds interaction to it apart from that, you know
我们也拥有人们最初用于创建数据的实际工具，比如关卡编辑器
we also have the actual tools that people use to author that data initially, like a level editor for example is probably
我想这是最简单的例子，你们大多数人可能听说过或用过
I think the simplest example that most of you have probably heard about or are used to
比如你们知道的，像那种东西，也是游戏引擎的一部分
you know, stuff like that, that's also part of a game engine
因为如果没有那些东西，我的意思是，你们可能就只有手动编写关卡了
because without that, I mean you're probably going to be stuck actually writing out your levels manually
并且像C++代码之类的东西，显然对任何人来说都不是很有用
and like C++ code or something like that which obviously isn't going to be very very useful for anyone
所以游戏引擎是一个很重要的话题，这些神奇的引擎能够获取数据并进行转换
so game engines are really this huge kind of topic there, these amazing kind of engines really that take data transform them
但也提供了一种方法来真正地编写数据，并且那就是本系列将要讨论的
but also provide a way to actually author that data, and that's what this series is going to be about
这只是第一期，这个游戏系列的第一期，在这个系列中，我们将和你们一起看
this is the first episode, first official episode of the game mentioned series in which we're going to I'm going to along with you guys
这将会有很多社区互动，也会有很多社区支持
it's going to be a lot of community interaction, a lot of community support as well
我们将继续，我们将用C++从头开始构建一个游戏引擎
we're going to go ahead and we're going to build a game engine from scratch in C++
并且在我们决定也需要使用的任何其他语言中，比如C#，这是一种常见的语言
and in any other languages that we decided we need to use as well, like C# for example, it's a common one
并且这个学习过程将会花费很长时间，它将会非常深入
and this journey is going to take a really long time, it's going to be really in depth
我将把这当成一个教程系列，而不是看着自己编写一个游戏引擎，却只给出很少的解释
I'm going to treat this as a tutorial series, not like as I kind of watch me write a game engine with minimal explanation
实际上我将把它作为一门课程来教，我们将构建一个巨大的系统，对吧
I'm actually going to teach this as a course pretty much, and we're just going to build this huge kind of system, right
并且游戏引擎存在的原因之一是，现在的游戏已经变得非常复杂
and one of the reasons the game engines exist as well, remember is that games nowadays have become so complicated
如果我们没有这个平台来制作游戏，每次就只能从头开始
that if we were to not have that platform to build games upon, we would end up building everything from scratch every time
想想一个200人的团队在创造一款像《侠盗猎车手》之类的游戏，对吧
think about a team of 200 people making a game like, I don't know, grand theft auto or something like that, right
只是我突然想到的一个例子，可能有超过200人，也可能超过1000人
just example the top of my head, that's probably way more than 200 people, probably more like 1000
但不管怎样，想象一下他们试图一遍又一遍地重复构建同样的技术，就好像，那是不可能的
but anyway, right, picture them trying to reiterate kind of build the same technology over and over again, like, that's impossible
此外，像程序员这样的工程师不可能拥有制作这样一款游戏所需要的一切，对吧
and furthermore, engineers like programmers, right, can't be available for everything that is needed to make a game like that, right
这就是为什么工程师最终创造了所有这些工具，而内容创造者是艺术家
which is why engineers end up building all of these tools, that content creators are artists
不熟悉编程或工程的人实际上可以用来构建所有的内容
that aren't familiar with programming or engineering can actually use to build all the content
因为就像我刚才提到的，游戏引擎转换它们将数据和资产转换成你们在屏幕上看到的东西
because as I just mentioned, game engines convert they transform that data those assets into something that you see on the screen
这些资产从哪儿来，对吧，当然是内容创造者，所以当你们思考什么是游戏时
where do those assets come from right content creators, so really when you think about it what is a game
是一款关于编程的游戏，是一款关于编写代码的游戏，并不是这样的，对吧
well is a game about programming, is a game about writing code, and doing all that, well not really, right
而大型专业游戏则完全不是这么做的，他们只是获取数据并将它们呈现在屏幕上
big scale professional games aren't about that at all, they're about taking data and putting it on the screen
所以那就是游戏引擎所做的一切，并且那就是它的意义，它的关键在于，好的
so that's really all the game engine is doing, and that's kind of the point of it, the point of it is to say, okay
足够多的编程，足够多的代码来完成所有的事情，对吧
enough programming, enough writing code to do everything, right
我们要做的就是，为人们设计某种方式
all we're going to do is, design some kind of way for people
那些不熟悉编程的人来创建所有这些数据来编辑这些数据
who aren't familiar with programming to actually create all that data to authoral that data
当然，它们需要像脚本一样填充，但不是直接编程，对吧
of course they will need to be stuffed like scripting, but not direct programming, right
那是一种游戏引擎的概念，当然在那种情况下，我是比较一般化的
that's kind of the idea of a game engine, and of course I am being kind of general in that case
游戏需要许多实际的工程支持，但最理想的情况是像Unity这样的东西
there is a lot of actual engineering support required for games, but in the ideal case look at something like Unity
你们可以用非常少的脚本制作任何类型的非大型游戏，对吧
you can make pretty much any kind of non huge scale game with very minimal scripting, right
因为大部分的工作只是创建能够接收这些数据的系统，并在正确的时间将它们定位到屏幕上
because the bulk of the work is just creating systems that can take that data, and position them on the screen at the right time
也可以修复可能发生的不同事件
and also kind of cure different events that might happen
并增加与用户的互动，无论如何，我希望你们喜欢这个视频
and also add that kind of interaction with the user, anyway, I hope you guys enjoyed this video
如果你们喜欢的话，就为它点赞吧
if you did, you can hit that like button
当然也可以访问patreon.com/TheCherno来帮助支持这个系列
you can help support this series by going to patreon.com/TheCherno
你们会得到很多奖励，比如提前一周访问源代码，以及访问视频
you'll get many rewards, such as access to source code early, access to videos about a week early as well
所以所有这些视频都将提前一周发布，如果你们想看第二个视频，实际上已经在patreon上了
so all these videos will be up a week early, so if you want to watch their second videos, actually already up on patreon
所以你们现在就可以去看，但我们还有每月discord的聚会
so you can just watch that right now, but also we have like monthly hangouts on discord
还有私人的discord频道，支持这个系列的人会得到很多奖励
and there's private discord channels, and there's just so many rewards that you guys get for helping support this series
因为这对我来说真的很重要，我们要建立一个社区
because it's really important to me that we kind of build this as a community
你们的支持对我很重要，我希望你们喜欢这个视频，我等不及要看下一个了
and your support is very important to me, I hope you guys enjoyed this video, I can't wait to see in the next one
下节课我们将讨论所有我们将放入游戏引擎中的系统
next time we're going to talk about all the systems that we're going to kind of put into our game engine
然后，我们会度过最初的计划和设计阶段，我想简短地说一下
and then after, we kind of get over that initial planning and design stage which I do want to keep very brief
因为我们会，比如你们知道的，我们要设计完整个东西，然后才能开始编程
because we'll kind of, you know, we're going to design the whole thing, and then only then start programming
我们会边写边设计，但我们仍然需要定义它的范围
we're going to kind of design as we go, but we still have to kind of define the scope of this
这样我们就可以从正确的地方开始，而不是结束于反复重写代码，所以下次会计划好一切
so that we can start in the right place, and not end up rewriting code 1 billion times, so next time we're gonna kind of plan everything
在那之前，我们最终会从零开始创建一个新项目
and then up to that, we're gonna finally create that new project from scratch and get on with this
我会讲到设置这个所需的环境，以及所有那些东西
and I'll cover kind of setting up the environment that you need for this, and all of that stuff as well
所以别担心，这个是一步一步从头开始的，每一期
so don't worry, this is gonna be kind of step by step and from scratch, every episode
我已经等不及了，下次见，拜
I can't wait, I'll see you guys next time, goodbye